Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]



(Immediate Joiner) - Android App Developer seeking roles in Android Development with 7 years experience



Current Designation: Android App Developer with 7 years

experience - Immediate joiner

Current Company: Edooni Solutions Pvt. Ltd

Current Location: Noida

Pref. Location: Noida, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Android, Kotlin, Android Development, Mobile Application Development, Android SDK, Core Java

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

7 years of IT experience in Software Development on the Android Platform using Java Programming language and Kotlin.

Expert at Java SDK design functionality, including the full activity lifecycle

Have worked with version control system like GIT.

Expertise on designing and developing Android Mobile Applications.

Expertise on HTTP, HTTPS and SSL Certification.

Expertise on PayUMoney, Google API Implementation, Google Map and Facebook Integration, FireBase.

Expertise on Volley, Retrofit, Glide and UIL Library.

Expertise on Push Notification using FCM.

Experience on working with databases Sqlite and ROOM.

Good analytical, Verbal and Written communication skills.

Good team player as per the assigned role i.e. whether it?s about leading the team or as an individual contributor.

Work Experience

Edooni Solutions Pvt. Ltd as Android App Developer with 7 years experience - Immediate joiner Sep 2019 to Till Date

Collaborate with a small, autonomous team of developers, designers, and product owners to find end-to-end solutions to important problems

Implement these solutions for our Android client, adhering to Android development best practices

Help your team solve problems in a way that makes sense for Android users and our codebase

Join other developers and help to shape the direction of Android development at our company

Insist on a consistent and responsive user experience for every one of our users

Continue to learn, grow, and help us tackle brand new challenges

AIG Technologies as Senior Software Developer Mar 2019 to Aug 2019

National Informatics Centre as Senior Software Developer Jun 2017 to Mar 2019

Education

UG: B.Com (Commerce) from Delhi University in 2010

PG: MCA (Computers) from Maharishi Dayanand University (MDU), Rohtak in 2013

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

A Level

Java & Android

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	ast Used Experience	
ANDROID		2020	6 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
JAVA		2020	6 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
Kotlin		2020	1 Year(s) 6 Month(s)	
Android Studio		2020	6 Year(s)	
SQLITE		2019	5 Year(s)	
GIT		2020	3 Year(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

Projects

Project Title: Test My Prep

Client: ALLEN CAREER INSTITUTE Nature of Employment: Full Time

Project Location: Noida Role: Sr. Programmer

Skill Used: Android, Kotlin

Role Description: Development, Testing

Project Details: Test My Prep (Online TestSeries.in) is the best Mobile App for online entrance (competitive) exam preparation to practice free Online Mock Tests for IITJEE(Main + Advanced), NEET-UG, BITSAT, NTSE, Olympiads, CBSE Class 6th to 10th.

Project Title: Pre-PG Test My Prep Client: ALLEN CAREER INSTITUTE Nature of Employment: Full Time

Project Location: Noida Role: Sr. Programmer Skill Used: Android, Kotlin

Role Description: Development, Testing

Duration: Sep 2019 - Sep 2020

Duration: Sep 2019 - Sep 2020 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Team Size: 3

Team Size: 3

Project Details: ALLEN Career Institute, India's leading and the best Coaching Institute for Pre-Medical and Pre-Engineering entrance (competitive) exam preparation, now enters into the Pre-PG (Medical) preparation with its 'ALLEN Pre-PG Test My Prep' Mobile App to give you the much needed extra edge and boost needed for your preparation, ably support by the parent website www.prepg.onlinetestseries.in .

Project Title: GATE Test My Prep Client: ALLEN CAREER INSTITUTE Nature of Employment: Full Time

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Sep 2019 - Sep 2020 Project Location: Noida Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 3

Skill Used: Android, Kotlin

Role Description: Development, Testing

Project Details: India's #1 Mock Test Practice app for GATE exam preparation by ALLEN.

Project Title: Census 2021 - Houselist Client: Registrar General's Department

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2018 - Mar 2019
Project Location: Delhi Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 3

Skill Used: Android, Java

Role Description: Concept, Designing, Development, Testing, Realease, Support, Pesentation, and Documentation... Project Details: This App is developed for Pre-Test of Houselisting and Housing Census to be conducted in April 2020 to September 2020. This App is developed by Office of The Registrar General, India.

Project Title: Census 2021 - Household Client: Registrar General's Department

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2018 - Mar 2019
Project Location: Delhi Duration: Jan 2018 - Mar 2019
Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 3

Skill Used: Android, Java

Role Description: Concept, Designing, Development, Testing, Realease, Support, Pesentation, and Documentation... Project Details: This Application is developed to collect the Population Enumeration Data by canvassing the HouseHold eForm, door-to-door, by the Enumerator. This is only to be used by the Official nominated by the State Government /Government of India to perform the Census operation.

Project Title: Census 2021 - NPR Client: Registrar General's Department

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jun 2017 - Feb 2019
Project Location: Delhi Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 3

Skill Used: Android. Java

Role Description: Concept, Designing, Development, Testing, Realease, Support, Pesentation, and Documentation... Project Details: NPR Updation Utility for pre-test. Only meant for Field Functionaries registered in Web Portal.

Project Title: Mission Antyodaya Client: National Informatic centre Nature of Employment: Full Time

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jun 2017 - Mar 2019
Project Location: Delhi Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 3

Skill Used: Android, Java

Role Description: Concept, Designing, Development, Testing, Realease, Support, Pesentation, and Documentation...

Project Details: Gram Panchayat Questionnaire for collecting Village level infrastructure data...

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time